Literacy Volunteers of America (LVA) Records
Literacy Volunteers of America (LVA) Records
- Colvin, Ruth J. (I)
  - Tutor Training
    - Workshop, 1977 (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965-1976; 1986-1989 (Box 33)
- General files (II)
  - Amos, Wally, 1979-1981 (Box 33)
  - Amos, Wally, 1982-1983; PR, press releases (Box 33)
  - "Read On!" Let Me Tell You a Story (Box 33)
  - Reports, final, 1986-1987; 4 folders (Box 33)
  - Reports, final, 1988; 4 folders (Box 34)
  - Speech material (Box 34)
- Colvin, Ruth J. (II)
  - Australia. "Learn Your Language" / Stocker, Margrit, 2 copies (Box 34)
  - New Zealand, "Adult Reading and Learning Assistance Federation of New Zealand, 1983; miscellaneous (Box 34)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 34)
  - Vietnamese
    - "Guide to Language and life in the U.S.A." (Box 35)
    - "Handbook for Teachers of Vietnamese Students: Hints for Dealing with Cultural Differences in Schools" / Bihn, Duong Thanh, in collaboration with Anne-Marie Diller, Kenton Sutherland, Arlington VA, Center for Applied Linguistics, 1975 (Box 35)
    - A Colloquium on The Vietnamese Language (Quang, Binh, and Sutherland), July 15, 1975; lva_406; includes cassette tape (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 35)
  - Visit Reports (Box 35)
  - "Way With Words. the Story of Literacy Volunteers of America" / Colvin, Ruth J, 1983 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965-1976; 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 35)
- General files (III)
  - Printouts of Basic Reading texts (Oversize 1)
  - Printouts of Basic Reading texts (Oversize 2)
  - Certificate, New Mexico, Jan. 30, 1985 (Oversize 2)
- General files (IV)
  - Action project, 1974 (Box 35)
  - Aging slides, 1986-1988 (Box 35)
  - B. Dalton Student Achievement LITMIS projects, 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Basic Reading Workshop script, 1972; 1976 (Box 35)
  - Bibliography, 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Board committees, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Board resignations, 1967-1977; 1986 (Box 35)
  - "Can your employees read this?", June 1984; photopcies of article (Box 35)
  - Colvin, Ruth, USA trip file, 1984-1985 (Box 36)
  - ESL hospital awareness, 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - ESL printed material (Box 36)
  - History of LVA (Box 36)
  - House, Palmer Road (Box 36)
  - Inner city recruitment project PEACE
    - Advisory committee (Box 36)
    - Program reports (Box 36)
    - Proposals/contracts (Box 36)
    - Publicity (Box 36)
    - Receipts/disbursements (Box 36)
  - LVA national staff development project, 1974 (Box 36)
  - LVA, Inc., August 6, 1980 (Box 36)
  - LVA NYS corrections project, 1974-1976 (Box 34)
  - Migrant script project, 1974 (Box 36)
  - NEH bibliography, 1979 (Box 37)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, Bibliography of Humanistic Reading for Grade Levels 1-8, 1978-1979 (Box 37)
  - NJ slide show script, 1988 (Box 37)
  - Patient communcation handbook
    - Correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box 37)
    - Design, 1988 (Box 37)
    - Research (Box 37)
  - "Read on!" promotional mailing (Box 37)
  - R&D questionnaire, 1978 (Box 37)
  - R2R [Right to read?], Literacy Volunteers New York City, 1975-1979; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Sample folder given to prospective donors, 1977-1978 (Box 38)
  - Teen Tutoring Program, 1971-1978 (Box 38)
  - Video project articles (Box 38)
  - Literacy articles and clippings, various publications, 64 folders (Box 38)
  - Literacy articles and clippings, various publications, 44 folders (Box 39)
- Media, audiovisual
  - Audiotape, reel to reel
    Reels listed without a box number should be requested using the ID number, for example "lva_061."
    - 5B-0576; REEL “A” PHONICS, lva_056; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - 5B-0576; REEL “B” WORD PATTERNS, lva_061; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - [Additional Techniques - Learning Disabilities, segment K-3] 4B-2275; A, lva_054; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - [Additional Techniques - Learning Disabilities, segment K-3] 4B-2275; =B=, lva_055; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Basic Reading Workshop. Overview. 2A-0177, lva_060; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Brown - Machell, lva_080; running time 14:13; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - C of C broadcast, "(Choral music - Alleluia Chorus, etc.) (No use to L.V. - but lovely music)", lva_079; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - Coleman, Samuel, 06/03/1966; lva_074; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
    - Colvin, Ruth; interview with Mary Ross (student), 02/24/1969; lva_075; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
    - Comprehension, 8A-1178
      - [Comprehension] 8A-1178; A, lva_047; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [Comprehension] 8A-1178; B, lva_048; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [Comprehension] 8A-1178; D, lva_049; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [Comprehension] 8A-1178; C, lva_050; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [Comprehension] 8A-1178; E, lva_051; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [Comprehension] 8A-1178; F, lva_052; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - English as a Second Language Series, 6 segments, 1/4 inch audio tape
      - ESL-A; SIDE I, lva_065; running time 20:56; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
      - ESL-A; SIDE II, lva_066; running time 13:28; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
      - ESL-B, lva_067; running time 9:56; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
      - ESL-C, lva_068; running time 13:37; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
      - ESL-D, lva_069; running time 16:11; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
      - ESL-E, lva_070; running time 22:20; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
      - ESL-F, lva_071; running time 10:06; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
    - "ESL Overview." 12B-1175, lva_059; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - ESL, 9A-0776
      - ESL-SEG “G”, 9A-0776; A, lva_058; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - ESL-SEG “H”, 9A-0776; B, lva_062; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Intercultural Communication. 8B-0978, lva_057; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Lillie Pope's speech Oct. 6, 1976, lva_077; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
    - Literacy Volunteers, lva_082; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - Literacy Volunteers, Inc., lva_076; Back of box says, “Blank tape.”; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
    - LVA segments F-1, 10C-2987, lva_017; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - LVA segment F-2, 10C-2987, lva_018; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - LVA segment G-2, 10C-2987, lva_019; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - "LVA-1" and "Spelling (K-1 & LVA) M7A093, lva_064; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - M5B-223, titles given in the finding aid are "Word By Word" "Lesson Goals" and "Motivation" but unable to determine which reel is which title
      - M5B-223; A, lva_024; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - M5B-223; B; SEG - =K-2=, lva_025; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - M5B-223; SEG =I=; B, lva_072; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
      - M5B-223; SEG =J=; B, lva_073; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
    - PHONICS DRILL; 11:47, lva_053; running time 11:47; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Sam Tape Copy I, lva_086; running time 6:30; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - Sam Tapes (Shortened Version) Copy 5, lva_087; running time 6:30; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - Sammy interview (for state fair), lva_078; running time 11:00; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 44)
    - "Sensitivity." MIE-103, lva_023; running time 10:38; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - "Something to Give, Something to Gain", lva_081; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - Sub master, section 3 session 13, lva_085; running time 6:30; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - T.T.W. - Overview. 1A-295, lva_063; probably "Tutor Training Workshop" of some kind; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Blank reel, lva_088; crossed-out notes originally said: “Dr. Frank Laubach edited by Colvin; Copy 5.”; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
    - Unidentified reels
      The following 42 reels could not be specifically identified. They may or may not be any of the following, which were listed in the original inventory but could not be matched to specific items: "Basic Reading Tapes. M6B-282 (20 reels)" "Basic Reading T. T. Workshop (9 reels)" "English as a Second Language, Lit. Volun. ESL A-F. 5A 144 (8 reels)" "ESL Interview" "ESL. 1980 series. Segments 1-8 (Films of these were never made. LVA has never used these.) (9 reels)" and "LVA. ESL. segments 5A-144 A-F."
      - [unidentified] =D= 26:03; Side #I, lva_001; running time 26:03; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] =A=, lva_002; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] A-10:49, lva_003; running time 10:49; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] “B”, lva_004; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] B-17:43; Side I, lva_005; running time 17:43; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] B-14:35; Side II, lva_006; running time 14:35; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] =C=, lva_007; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] C-12:39, lva_008; running time 12:39; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] =D=, lva_009; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] =F=, lva_010; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] =G=, lva_011; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] “D” - 14:44; Side #II, lva_012; running time 14:44; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] =E=, lva_013; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] E - 16:40, lva_014; running time 16:40; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] “F” - 25:43; Side #I, lva_015; running time 25:43; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] “F” - 23:22; Side #II, lva_016; running time 23:22; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] G”-18:12, lva_020; running time 18:12; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] =H=, lva_021; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] H-I 7:08; 10 SEC ROLL - HL+TL LDR - OP/CL FOIL -, lva_022; running time 7:08; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] V/M (A)(B1)(B2), lva_026; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] V/M-A-B+C; 5A-144, lva_027; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] V/M (C)(D)(E), lva_028; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] F/M - SEG A; F/M, lva_029; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] F/M - SEG B1; F/M - SEG B2; F/M, lva_030; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] F/M - SEG C; F/M, lva_031; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] F/M - SEG D; F/M, lva_032; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] F/M - SEG E; F/M, lva_033; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] F/M - SEG. F(A); F/M, lva_034; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] F/M - SEG F(B); F/M, lva_035; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG I - SIDE I, lva_036; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG #1; SIDE 2, lva_037; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG #2, lva_038; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG #3, lva_039; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG 4 - SIDE I, lva_040; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG 4; SIDE -2-, lva_041; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG. #5 - V/M_F/M -; ESL - SEG #5 TESTING -; F/M - VERIFIED; 8:43, lva_042; running time 8:43; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG 6A, lva_043; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] 6-B -, lva_044; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG 8 - SIDE I, lva_045; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG #8; SIDE 2, lva_046; 1/4 inch audio tape
      - [unidentified] SEG “B” - 2 TRACK, lva_083; running time 32:52; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
      - [unidentified] Side 1, lva_084; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 45)
  - Audiotape, cassettes
    - ALA [American Library Association], "Literacy and Public Libraries," Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York
      - ALA - Side 1; Side 2: Literacy & Public Libraries, lva_137; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - ALA - Side 1; Side 2: Lit. & Public Libraries, lva_138; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - ALA - Side 1; Side 2: Lit & Public Libraries, lva_139; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - ALA - Side 3: Lit & Public Libraries, lva_140; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - ALA - Side 3: Lit & Public Libraries, lva_141; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - ALA - Side 3: Lit & Public Libraries, lva_142; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
    - Basic Reading Skills, Book 1-8, Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York
      - Book 1, Unit 1 Orig; Book 1 - Unit 4 Orig., lva_109; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 1 Unit 2 Master, lva_110; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 1 Unit 3 Or., lva_111; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 1 Unit 5 - Master/Orig.; Book 3 Unit 15 - Master/Orig., lva_112; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 2 Unit 6-7 Master Tape, lva_113; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 2 Unit 8-9 Orig. Master Tape, lva_114; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 2 Unit 10 - Orig. Master, lva_115; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 3 Unit 11-12 Orig Master, lva_116; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 3 Unit 13-14 Orig. Master, lva_117; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 4 Tape 18-19 Orig Master, lva_118; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 4 Unit 20 Original Master, lva_119; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 5 Unit 21A New Master; Book 5 Unit 21B & 22A New Master, lva_120; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 5 Unit 22 cont. New Master; Book 5 Unit 23 New Master, lva_121; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 5 Unit 24; Unit 25 Master, lva_122; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 6 Tape 26; 27-A Master, lva_123; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 6 Tape 27-B; 28 Master, lva_124; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 6 Unit 29; 30 Master, lva_125; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 7 Unit 31-32 Master, lva_126; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 7 Unit 33-A; 33-B Master, lva_127; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 7 Unit 34; 35 Master, lva_128; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 8 - Unit 36 A & B Master, lva_129; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 8 Unit 37; 38 Master, lva_130; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
      - Book 8 Unit 39; 40 Master, lva_131; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
    - Basic Reading Tutor Training Workshop
      - Segmant A Introduction, lva_226; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment B, Language Experience, lva_227; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment C, Sight Words, lva_228; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment C, Sight Words, lva_229; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment D, Phonics (consonants) (2 cassettes), lva_230; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment E, Word Patterns, lva_231; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment F(a), Assessment / Goal Setting, lva_232; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment F(b), Goal Analysis / Lesson Planning, lva_233; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment G(2), Formal Assessment, lva_234; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Basic Reading Workshop
      - Overview, lva_186; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment A, Introduction, lva_207; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment B, Experience Story, lva_208; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment C, Sight Words (3 cassettes), lva_209, 210; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment D, Phonics (consonants), lva_211, 212; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment E, Word Patterns, lva_213, 214; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment G, Applying All Techniques, lva_215, 216; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment I, Lesson Plans and Goals, lva_217; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment J, Motivation and Reinforcement, lva_218; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment K-2, Fluency in Reading, lva_183, 184, 185; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Beckwith, Walter, Oct 1979; lva_167; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Beckwith, Walter, 1979; lva_168; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Colvin, Ruth
      - Nottingham Reading Program, Audio Magnetics Corp, Gardena, CA, 12/10/1973; lva_156; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Nottingham Reading Program, Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York, 12/10/1973; lva_157; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Nottingham Reading Program, Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York, 12/10/1973; lva_158; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Nottingham Reading Program, Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York, 12/10/1973; lva_159; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Test read, Larry Horn, 01/11/1974; lva_160; running time 90:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Using a Tape Recorder as Homework and Practice for ESL Students. LVA/ESL, Oct 1975; lva_161; running time 10:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Comprehension And Study Skills Part One, lva_187; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Comprehension And Study Skills Part Two, lva_188; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - English as a Second Language, 1980
      - Segment 1, Intercultural Communication, lva_219; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment 2, Introduction, lva_220; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment 3, Let's Get Started, lva_221; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment 4, Special Techniques, lva_222; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment 6B, Teaching Language Skills, lva_223; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment 7, Survival Skills and Teaching Materials, lva_224; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - Segment 8, Goals and Lesson Plans, lva_225; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - ESL, NYS Ruth Colvin, October 25, 1975; lva_162; running time 90:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - ESL, Reading, lva_146; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Greene, Dr. Frank, 09/27/1973; lva_163; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Greene, Dr. Frank, 09/27/1973; lva_164; running time 90:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - "I Can Go Anywhere" / Gene White, lva_180; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - "I Can Go Anywhere" / Gene White, lva_181; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Intercultural Communication, lva_189; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Intercultural Communication, lva_190; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Kussrow, Dr. Paul, Oct. 3, 1985; lva_171; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Literacy Volunteers: D. Raymond, lva_172; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Long Journey / Buon Norasing (ESL), lva_182; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Lugae, Hilda (Spanish), Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York
      - Spanish - Hilda Lugue, lva_149; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Hilda Lugue, 01/29/1974; lva_150; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Literacy Volunteers Story, Oct 1973; lva_145; running time 40:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Madrid, Francisca (Spanish), Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York
      - Spanish - Francisca Madrid - alphabet, colors, directions, lva_147; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Francisca Madrid - Testing, 01/22/1974; lva_148; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - News, April 10th, lva_178; running time 30:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Nicholson, Arthur May, May 1981; lva_170; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Perceptions, Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York, lva_143; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
    - Perceptions, Audio Visual Systems, Syracuse, New York, lva_144; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
    - "Probe" on Illiteracy in Washington, D.C. CBS, Nov. 22, 1980; lva_169; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Read On!, original inventory listes "Book 1-7 (42 cassettes) and Book 1-4 (91 cassettes)" but there are actually 153 tapes, and it was not possible to tell which tapes go with which set
      - Book 1, Units 1-5, lva_235 to 271; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 49)
      - Book 2, Units 6-10, lva_272 to 331; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
      - Books 3-7, Units 11-35, lva_332 to 387; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 51)
    - [Right to Read?] Philip PA; Frank FA, lva_407; originally found with boxes of slides in a Right To Read box; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 40)
    - [Right to Read?] Allen AA; Philip Slide Tape, lva_408; originally found with boxes of slides in a Right To Read box; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 40)
    - [Right to Read?] LVA ESL Human Interest Story (for slides/tapes), 1982; lva_409; originally found with boxes of slides in a Right To Read box. 1st Part - Christiana Molony - France - (b) Liu Dai (Peoples Rep. China/ Talk on Peking-Beijing) 5/16/92, Colvin; Lin Rui-Chang (Peoples Rep. China) talk on Status of Women - 5/16/82; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 40)
    - Root, Jane
      - Dr. Jane Root to LVA Staff Sides 1 & 2, 10-7-74; lva_151; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Dr. Jane Root to Staff 10-7-74 Sides 3 & 4, lva_152; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Dr. Jane Root to Staff 10-7-74 Sides 3 & 4, lva_153; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Dr. Jane Root to Staff 10-7-74 Sides 5 & 6, lva_154; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Sawyer, Dr. Diane, Nottingham Reading Program, Oct 1973; lva_155; running time 40:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Schizer, Boris, 10/25/1975; lva_165; running time 90:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Tadros, Nada
      - LVA tapes of Nada Tadros (Jordan) & Agnes Fox (Sides #1 & #2), lva_175; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - LVA tapes of Nada Tadros (Jordan) & Agnes Fox (Sides #3 & #4), lva_176; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - LVA tapes of Nada Tadros (Jordan) & Agnes Fox (Side #5), lva_177; running time 30:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - "To Read, To Speak, To Live!", lva_179; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - Vietnamese Family, New Year's Day 1976, 1 Jan 1976; lva_166; running time 90:00; Side No. 1: Uncle Bob, Aunt Ruth and the Pfam family from Viet Nam; Side No. 2: Instructional Workshop Session #2 - Section 6+7+8+9; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Waterman, Vurlean
      - Mrs. Vurlean Waterman from Dorothy Clark, 89 Hampton St. #104, Hartford, Connecticut 06120, (203) 247-4164., lva_173; running time 90:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
      - Vurlean Waterman, LVA, lva_174; running time 60:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 47)
    - Workshop for Tutors, ESL
      See also related slides.
      - A - Orientation, Listening Comp., Testing, lva_191, 192; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - B - Getting Started, lva_193, 194; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - C - Visual Aids, lva_195, 196; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - D - Teaching Language Skills, lva_197, 198; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - E - Special Techniques, lva_199, 200; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - F - Other Cultures, Citizenship, lva_201, 202; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - G - Survival Skills, lva_203, 204; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
      - H - Goals and Lesson Plans, lva_205, 206; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 48)
    - [unidentified] F-1, Riposo Studios, Syracuse, New York, lva_132; running time 18:04; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)